Guide to the National Education Association-Commissions records, 1918-1982 NEA1002.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- NEA Centennial Commission, 1946-1976; Series 8; 5 Linear Feet
  - Measure of Teacher Competences: Report of Special Group D, The Miami Beach Conference, 1953; series 8 (Box 4297, Folder 13)
  - Memo to Local Leaders, 1953; Series 8 (Box 1110, Folder 10)
  - Miami Beach Report, June 1953; Series 8 (Box 1110, Folder 11)
  - Midland Schools, November 1954; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 1)
  - A Minute for Teachers, 1956; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of CAP Committee Meetings, 1951; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 3)
  - National Education Association Journal Clippings on CAP, 1951-1952; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 4)
  - Newsletter Ideas, 1955-1957; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 5)
  - Notes from the Detroit Convention, 1951-1952; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 6)
  - Order Blank #1, 1953; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 7)
  - Other Anniversaries, 1956-1957; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, circa 1957; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 9)
    Contained 2 film negative rolls titled, "Winnie Mooney, Ridgeling Team", which has been removed and placed in the media materials series.
  - The Profession of Education: A Syllabus, April 1958; series 8 (Box 4987, Folder 14)
  - The Professional Standards Movement in Teaching- As Recommened by the Parkland Conference Prepared for Use of State and Local TEPS Commissions, November 1956; series 8 (Box 4297, Folder 15)
  - Reports-"Don't Tell Me Teaching is a Soft Job!", 1954; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 10)
  - Reports-"Little Red Schoolhouse in the Middle of the Road", 1955; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 11)
  - Reports-"A McCalls Report on Report Cards", 1955; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 12)
  - Reports-"My Forty Children", 1955; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 13)
  - Reports-"National Teacher Examinations", 1956; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 14)
  - Reports-"I Rode the School Bus", 1955; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 15)
  - Reports-"Teaching is Hard Work", 1954; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 16)
  - Reports-"Textbooks Under Fire", 1955; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 17)
  - Reports-"Tomorrow's Illiterates", circa 1957; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 18)
  - Reports-"The Truth About our Public Schools", 1954; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 19)
  - Reports-"What a Good High School Should Do", 1955; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 20)
  - Reports-"Whats all the Fuss About Report Cards?", 1955; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 21)
  - Restaurant Association, 1956-1957; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 22)
  - Saint Mary's Report, June 1952; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 23)
  - Sales Statements, 1957-1958; Series 8 (Box 1111, Folder 24)
  - Scholarships, Fellowships, and Student-Aid Programs for Students Planning to Be Public-School Teachers, June 1954; series 8 (Box 4297, Folder 16)
  - The Search for New Frontiers: Keynote Address 1958 TEPS Conference, ca. 1958; series 8 (Box 4297, Folder 17)
  - The Seven Cardinal Principles Revisted, 1976; series 8 (Box 4347, Folder 5)
  - Skits and Dramas, 1953-1957; Series 8 (Box 1112, Folder 1)
  - Slater Food Service Management, 1957; Series 8 (Box 1112, Folder 2)
    Contains NEA seal stickers, napkin and placemat.
  - Sources of Material for Various Pages, 1951; Series 8 (Box 1112, Folder 3)
  - Statements, 1955-1958; Series 8 (Box 1112, Folder 4)
  - Dr. Street Records, 1955; Series 8; Street, Paul (Box 1112, Folder 5)
  - Suggestions for the Theme, 1954-1955; Series 8 (Box 1112, Folder 6)
  - Teacher Selective Recruitment Programs: A How-To-Do-IT Action Bulletin, 1952; series 8 (Box 4297, Folder 18)
  - Thank-Yous-Contacts, 1955-1957; Series 8 (Box 1112, Folder 7)
  - Tribute and Publicity for Retirement of Harrison Fry, July 1957; Series 8 (Box 1112, Folder 8)
    Fry, Harrison
  - Unified Dues Proposal, circa 1951; Series 8 (Box 1112, Folder 9)
  - "What Faith Have Teachers", 1956-1957; Series 8 (Box 1112, Folder 10)
  - Work Copies for CAP Projects, 1951; Series 8 (Box 1112, Folder 11)
- Legislative Commission, 1921-1960; Series 9; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Historical Note
  The Commission was created in 1920 to continue the work done by the Joint Commission on the Emergency in Education. It was responsible for recommending the federal legislative policies supported by the National Education Association, and working to see those policies adopted.
  Series is arranged alphabetically by title.
  Scope and Contents
  Series contains records created or held by the Legislative Commission as part of its duties. The contents are primarly published material, including pamphlets.
  - Children, Teachers, and Retirement Laws, 1934; series 9 (Box 4312, Folder 19)
  - Legislative Commission Pamphlets, 1921, 1959; series 9 (Box 4312, Folder 20)
  - Pamphlet, December 1960; series 9 (Box 4383, Folder 12)
  - School Legislation Affecting Young Children, January 1935; series 9 (Box 4312, Folder 21)
  - Speaker's Guide and Script: Breakthrough to Better Schools, January 1959; series 9 (Box 4400, Folder 6)